# Yuri Bochkarev May 24, 1988

Moscow (Russia) • baltazar.bz@gmail.com • +79853037426 • linkedin • bitbucket • github

## **Summary**

Linux Python backend developer with total of over 10 years of experience in building, testing and maintaining complex software systems. 5+ years of Python experience, 6+ years of C++ experience, solid low-level background. Driven to get things done along with learning new skills, tools and technologies. Skills to write efficient, maintainable and tested code. Able to communicate effectively and clearly in Russian and English both spoken and written.

## **Experience**

IPONWEB – media trading platform (RTB, Ad exchange, DSP, SSP)

Moscow

#### **Senior Software Developer (Technology)**

May 2016 – present

- Backend implementation of campaign visualization and forecasting service (Python, Django, Numpy, Scipy, Pandas)
- Software development process: Scrum + Kanban

## **Software Developer (Technology)**

July 2014 - May 2016

- Backend implementation of campaign visualization and forecasting service (Python, Django, Numpy, Scipy, Pandas)
- · Participation in development of budget control server for advertising campaigns (Python, Twisted, Numpy, Pandas)
- Roll out and support of Continuous Integration infrastructure (Jenkins, Trial, pytest, custom testing stands)

#### Software Developer (R&D)

January 2013 – July 2014

September 2009 – January 2013

· Support, development, and architechture refactoring of data delivery service (Python, BASH, Django)

SmartLabs – interactive digital television (IPTV, DVB, OTT TV)

Moscow

#### **System Department Developer**

- Development of video content viewing redirector (C++, Qt)
- Development of video content distribution automation tool (C++, Qt)
- Integration of automation tool with existing platform
- Participation in SmartMedia platform video server development (C++, Qt, STL, live555)
- Implementation of adaptive streaming client (C++, Qt, Apple HTTP Streaming)
- Development of platform components build automation tool (Python)
- Participation in adaptive streaming server development (Python, Twisted)
- · Accompanying protocols: HTTP, XML RPC, SOAP, RTSP

Autoscan Ulyanovsk

## Software Developer

*September 2007 – May 2009* 

- Development of network applications for real-time video transmission (C++, Qt, OPAL, libjingle)
- Automation of application's testing (AutoIt, Erlang)
- Accompanying protocols: XMPP, SIP, RTP, STUN

# Ulyanovsk State Technical University

Ulyanovsk

Technician

September 2006 – September 2007

- Computer class administration (11 computers, ASP Linux 9.0, Microsoft Windows 2003)
- · Class video surveillance organization, technical support

# **Education**

#### Ulyanovsk State Technical University

Ulyanovsk 2007 – 2009

**Master's degree**, Faculty of Information Systems & Technologies, diploma VMA 0105774 **Bachelor's degree**, Faculty of Information Systems & Technologies, diploma AVB 0512119

2003 – 2007

#### **Additional Education**

Information Technology Alliance		coursera.org	
Clojure Course	April 2013	Machine Learning: Classification	April 2016
udacity.com Programming a Robotic Car Artificial Intelligence coursera.org Computing for Data Analysis Algorithms: Design and Analysis, Part I Machine Learning	1	Game Theory (HSE)	March 2016
	April 2012 December 2011 October 2012 April 2012 December 2011	Machine Learning: Regression	February 2016
		ML Foundations: A Case Study Approach	February 2016
		Cloud Computing Applications	October 2015
		Image and Video Processing	March 2015
		Algorithmic Thinking	November 2014
		Cryptography, Part I	June 2014
		Write Like Mozart	March 2014
		Discrete Optimization	August 2013
		Functional Programming Principles in Scala	December 2012

## **Skills**

**Technical** OS: GNU/Linux (since 2009), Windows (2001 – 2009). Programming Languages: Python, C++. Moderately experienced as well in: Go, Haskell, Clojure, R, Scala, Erlang, Lua, AutoIt, Java, Octave, x86 assembler. VCS: hg, git, svn. Technologies: Unit Testing, Design Patterns, UML. Frameworks: Twisted, Pyramid, Django, Pandas, Scipy. **Language** Russian (*native*), English (*upper intermediate*).